生活大爆炸前情提要
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
Sheldon  难道你刚刚是想出了
Sheldon, did you just figure out
合成新型稳定超重元素的方法了?
a method for synthesizing a new stable super-heavy element?
我有吗?!
Did I?!
这不太可能
Well, that can't be right.
这事前无古人啊
No one's ever done that before.
除了我  因为我刚刚做到啦!
Except me because I just did it!
# Sheldon和他的大脑  万岁! #
# Sheldon and his brain, yeah
# Sheldon and his brain, yeah! #
我犯了一个致命的错误
I've made a horrible mistake.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这个表格  单位是平方厘米
This table, it's in square centimeters
我把它当成平方米读了
I read it as square meters.
你知道意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
美国人搞不定公制单位?
That Americans can't handle the metric system?
Amy  我差了整整1万倍
Amy, I was off by a factor of 10,000.
但是中国科学家找到了该元素
But the Chinese team found the element.
是啊  他们不该找到的
Yeah, well, they shouldn't have.
我的计算有误
My calculations were wrong.
我一生中最重要的发现
The greatest scientific achievement of my life
却是来自一个错误
is based on a blunder.
我不是个天才
I'm not a genius.
而是个骗子
I'm a fraud.
Sheldon你要知道  在神经学里
You know, Sheldon, in neuroscience,
我们永远会在大脑某部分发现
we're forever finding something in one part of the brain
本以为在其他地方的东西
that we thought was someplace else.
噢  太好了  我现在连骗子都不如
Oh, great, now I'm worse than a fraud.
我成生物学家了
I'm practically a biologist.
这是科学星期五  我是Ira Flatow
This is Science Friday. I'm Ira Flatow.
我们今天的嘉宾是发现首个稳定超重元素的
My guest today is responsible for the discovery of the first
科学家
stable super-heavy element.
欢迎  Sheldon Cooper博士
Welcome, Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
谢谢
Thank you.
唔  学校叫我过来的
Uh, the university made me come here.
我一点也不想来
I didn't want to.
厄  我是这个节目的粉丝
Uh, big fan of the show.
那么  我知道你实际上是误打误撞
So, I understand that you actually discovered
才找到这个元素的
this element by mistake.
是的
Yes.
在科学圈里有人把这个现象称作
And some people in the science community are calling it
"神奇的大错误"
"The Wonder Blunder."
谁说的?  把他们名字告诉我
Who? Give me their names.
我打赌肯定是Wolowitz
I bet it's Wolowitz.
这真是个神奇的故事
It's just such a fascinating story.
你的计算差的十万八千里
Your calculations are way off,
但是他们却找到了这个元素
but they find the element anyway.
就好像读错了藏宝图
It's like misreading a treasure map
却仍找到了宝藏
and still finding the treasure.
我们能聊聊其他的吗?
Can we talk about something else?
你知道我会约德尔唱法吗?
Do you know that I yodel?
有意思  但是这个发现有可能会帮你
That's interesting, but this could be taking you
打通获得诺贝尔奖之路
down the path toward a Nobel Prize.
毫无疑问是化学奖
And in chemistry, no less.
不是很奇怪吗?
And wouldn't that be unusual?
因为你是个物理学家
Because you're a physicist.
是啊  是啊  我将会是个获得诺贝尔化学奖的物理学家
Yes, yes, I'd be a physicist with a Nobel in chemistry.
人人都会嘲笑这个马戏团的怪物
Everyone laugh at the circus freak.
你知道吗  Flatow  我没必要呆在这里忍受这些
You know, I don't need to sit here and take this, Flatow.
正是因为像你这些恶人
It is because of bullies like you,
越来越多的美国人
every day more and more Americans
才选择看电视了
are making the switch to television.
本字幕由  谢耳朵字幕组  翻译制作
更多生活大爆炸剧集，访谈及资讯
请关注新浪围脖  @谢耳朵字幕组
翻译：南京小黑  高珊啊啊  卡布瑞￠浠
审校：冰之冷  压制：伍步书
招募审校, 美工, 资讯等  报名qq群 186040513
生活大爆炸第七季第十集
Seibert校长  我不知道为啥你要冲我吼
President Seibert, I don't know why you're yelling.
就是你逼我去上节目的
You're the one who made me go on the radio.
我还以为是一个专业的科学访谈
I was expecting a professional science interview,
而不是收到那些哗众取宠的名嘴的攻击
not an attack by some morning zoo shock jock.
好吧  如果大学这么需要钱
Well, if the university needs money so badly,
也许你应该准备一个脏话罐
(脏话罐: 说脏话就要向里面投钱的罐子)
perhaps you should start a swear jar.
哇!  你刚才说的话可要投一美金了
Whoa! That one's worth a dollar.
我知道你不喜欢这样
I know you don't like it,
但是每次你去参加访谈
but every time you do an interview,
都会增加学校的声誉
it raises the profile of the university.
那会带来更多的资助
That translates to funding.
是啊  但是我不是被训练
Yeah, well, I'm not just
靠跳舞来赚钱的猴子
some trained monkey dancing for coins.
你当然不是
Of course you're not.
人们喜欢那些猴子
People love trained monkeys.
你有什么好不开心的?
How can you not be happy?
你又高又瘦还出名
You're tall, thin and famous.
偶滴神啊  我居然在嫉妒Sheldon
Oh, my God, I'm jealous of Sheldon.
听着  你还得做这些事情做一段时间
Look, you're gonna be doing this stuff for a while.
你必须找到接受它的方法
You're just gonna have to find a way to get used to it.
你们没人能理解这种感受
But none of you know what this is like.
别人一直在庆祝一件你希望自己从没干过的事情
Being celebrated for something you wish you never did.
唔  你肯定没跟我去过狂欢节
Mmm... you clearly haven't been with me at Mardi Gras.
可以停一下游戏来帮我打扫一下吗?
Want to pause the video game and help me clean up?
我正在打扫呢
I am cleaning up.
看看小丑把这哥谭市弄得一团糟
Look at the mess the Joker made of Gotham City.
拜托  要过来住的可是你哥们
Come on, it's your friend who's coming to stay here.
Raj在印度长大
Raj grew up in India.
相信我  他看过更乱的
Trust me, he's seen worse.
Howie!
Howie.
我保证在接下来的这一周
I promise I'll help out
我会帮你打扫的
the rest of the week.
接下来的这一周?
The rest of the week?
你说只是住一两天
You said it was just gonna be a night or two.
好吧  如果我说住一个礼拜
Yeah, but if I told you a week,
你会同意吗?
would you have said yes?
-不!  -那你让我没得选啦
-No! -Then you left me no choice.
我喜欢Raj  但是这也住的太久啦
I love Raj, but that's a long time for a house guest.
我知道  但是他们在装修大楼
I know, but they're tenting his building.
而且他也找不到既能让狗住又让他满意的酒店
He can't find a hotel he likes that allows dogs.
他还要带着肉桂儿?
He's bringing Cinnamon?
在这住一个礼拜!
For a whole week!
某些人胆子实在太大了
The nerve of some people.
尴尬快车来了
Here comes the Embarrassment Express.
将要在欺诈市
With stops at Fraudville...
神奇的大错误山
WonderBlunderberg...
还有堪萨斯城停车
and Kansas City.
因为它是个中转站
Because it's a hub.
Sheldon  我能进来吗
Sheldon, can I come in?
-你有曲奇饼吗  -没有
-Do you have cookies? -No.
好  我不配吃曲奇饼  进来吧
Good. I don't deserve cookies. Come in.
Wil...?
嗨  Sheldon
Hey, Sheldon.
好久没见
It's been a while.
你来干啥?
Why are you here?
Amy告诉我你最近过的不好
Amy said you were having a rough time,
我想也许我们能聊聊
and I thought maybe we could talk.
可以吗?
Is that okay?
当然
Certainly.
尽管...
Although...
现在我就感到很不舒服
right now, I'm having a rough time
因为有三个人在我的房间里
because there's three people in my room,
感觉像是在迪斯科舞厅一样
and it's starting to feel like a discotheque.
Sheldon你说你因为别人总是注意那些
Sheldon, you said you were unhappy getting attention
你希望自己从未做过的事而不开心
for something you wished you never did.
嗯  我处理这些有点经验
Yeah, I know a little something about that.
哦  Wil你胡说
Oh, nonsense, Wil.
你没完没了的微博没有那么挫啦
Your endless tweets are not that bad.
我想起来为什么这么久没见他了
I remember why it's been a while.
Sheldon  我说的是我小时候
Sheldon, I was actually talking
演星际迷航的事情
about when I was a kid on Star Trek.
你怎么会不喜欢
How could you not like getting attention
扮演Wesley Crusher带来的关注
for playing Wesley Crusher?
你演的很棒啊
You were wonderful.
一个拥有高清记忆能力无所不知的天才少年
A know-it-all boy genius with an eidetic memory.
谁不会感同身受?
Who couldn't relate to that?
额  不是所有人这么想的
Well, not everybody felt that way.
好多人讨厌那个角色
A lot of people really hated the character,
还有人因为这个角色而讨厌我
and some of them hated me because of it.
我上访谈节目
I would do interviews,
那些人对我也很苛刻
and people would be mean to me.
我也是这样
That just happened to me.
下次你疯狂发微博的时候
Next time you're stuck for a tweet,
你可以吐槽Ira Flatow的坏人品
feel free to say what a jerk Ira Flatow is.
Sheldon关键是Wil学会接受那段生活
Sheldon, the point is Wil learned to embrace
然后向更美好的方向继续前行
that part of his life and moved on to bigger and better things.
是啊  我现在是个作家
Yeah, I'm an author now,
我还会做一些公共演说
I do public speaking,
而且我还有一些关于棋盘游戏的网站
and I have my own Web series about board games.
额...
Uh...
我们是想让他开心  所以...
We're trying to cheer him up, so...
我想说的是我曾经一度以为
I'm just saying that there was a time
我再也无法逃脱Wesley Crusher的阴影的
when I thought I would never get out of Wesley Crusher's shadow.
但是现在
But now,
那只是我快乐生活的一小部分
it's just one small part of a pretty great life,
而且我很高兴我度过了那样一段时光
and it's a part that I'm happy is there.
我知道你想说什么了
I do see what you're saying.
很有帮助
That helps.
太好了
Good.
你们俩想留下来
Would you two like to stay
和我一起玩火车游戏吗?
and play trains with me?
-当然  -没问题
-Sure. -Okay.
太好了
Oh, great!
现在...
Now...
我负责控制
I work the controls.
我说"开动了"
I say "All aboard"
你们就静静的坐着看
You sit quietly and watch.
我能吹口哨吗?
Can I blow the whistle?
你还是走吧
You should probably go.
你这是要在我沙发上刷牙么?
You're gonna brush your teeth on my couch?
不  我是要刷肉桂儿的牙
No, I'm gonna brush Cinnamon's teeth.
何必呢?
Why bother?
一半的时间她都是在舔屁屁
She spends half the time licking her butt.
还有一半时间是在舔我的脸
And the other half licking my face.
所以我要给她刷牙
That's why I'm brushing her teeth.
嘿  不好意思回来晚了
Hey, guys. Sorry I'm so late.
你们吃过晚饭了吗?
Did you already have dinner?
没呢  在等你
No, we were waiting for you.
你们太贴心了
Aw, that's so sweet.
那当然  所以你打算做什么晚饭?
Yeah. So what do you feel like making?
Howard  你的小可怜刚刚工作回来呢
Howard, the poor thing just got home from work.
我去给你倒杯酒
Let me get you a glass of wine.
我来做饭
I'll cook dinner.
-别啊Raj  你是客人  -客气啥呢
-Oh, Raj, you're our guest.  -Don't be silly.
你坐  看起来你累了一天了
Sit. You look like you've had a long day.
她看起来总是那样
No, she always looks like that.
因为她嫁给了一个白痴
Because she married an idiot.
谢谢你  Raj
Thank you, Raj.
没事儿  这是我感谢的方式
Please, this is my way of thanking you
谢谢你们让我住在这
for letting me stay here.
来  说说你今天怎么样
Now, tell us all about your day.
好的呢  首先呢
Okay, um, well, first,
我开会迟到了  因为堵在路上了
I was late to a meeting 'cause I was stuck in traffic.
我一直叫你手机里安一个实时交通软件的
Well, I keep telling you to put that traffic app on your phone.
喂喂  你今天回家
Hey, when you got home today complaining
抱怨吃太多软糖不大舒服的时候
that you felt sick from eating too many jelly beans,
我对你指手画脚了吗?
did I tell you how to fix it?
没有!
No.
我跟你说了 "一定很难受吧"  然后摸了摸你的肚子
I said, "Aw, that must hurt," and I rubbed your belly.
我一直都在想着你
I thought of you the whole time.
我想说的就是  有时候你就该安静倾听
All I'm saying is there's a time to just listen.
谢谢
Thank you.
有时候你也得控制不吃太多软糖
There's also a time to stop eating too many jelly beans.
你十岁的时候就该这么做了
And it's when you're ten.
你好  Siebert主席
Hello, President Siebert.
谢谢你接了我的电话
Thank you for taking my call.
我只是想告诉你  本人现在会非常有热情的
I just wanted you to know that you can now expect
参加你鉴于我的重大发现安排的活动
enthusiastic participation from me regarding my discovery.
不不不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
没必要谢我
No need to thank me.
谢谢我的朋友  Wil Wheaton
Thank my friend, Wil Wheaton.
我可以告诉你   我可是有9位朋友
For your information, I have nine friends, hmm?
算上你的话有10位哦
Ten if we include you.
那就9位吧
Nine it is.
还是算10位吧
Ah, it's ten.
Wolowitz也算上
I'll count Wolowitz.
你好  我的朋友Leonard
Hello, friend Leonard.
你心情不错哟
Hey, you're in a good mood.
我心情大好
I'm in a great mood.
你马上就要心情更好了
Well, you're about to be in an even better one.
本来还不确定的时候我不想说的  但是...
I didn't want to say anything until I knew for sure, but...
我一直在实验室重复测试你的元素
I've been re-running the tests on your element in my lab
而且我已经证明它错误了
and I disproved it.
你的元素根本不存在
Your element does not exist!
但那些中国科研团队是怎么回事?
Yeah, but what about the Chinese research team?
他们明明发现了
They found it.
应该是有人在数据文件里加了模拟信号
Yeah, it turns out someone added simulated signals to the data files.
他们伪造试验结果
They faked the results.
真的?
Really?
是呀! 你知道这意味着什么不?
Yes! Do you know what that means?
这意味着你厌恶的所有瞩目都烟消云散了
That means all of this attention that you hate goes away.
所以再也没有什么访问接见了?
So no more interviews?
没有  都没有了
No, it's all over.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
不谢
Well, you're welcome.
你夺走了我最伟大的成就!
You robbed me of my greatest achievement!
啥?!
What?!
重新回到9位朋友的生活!
I'm back down to nine friends!
还是8位吧... 我也受够Wolowitz了!
Make it eight... I'm sick of Wolowitz, too!
我不懂啊
I... I don't understand.
自从你发现该死的元素
All you've done since you discovered
你一直就是抱怨抱怨
this stupid element was complain.
我是想哄你开心啊!
I was trying to make you happy!
通过夺走我唯一的成名之举吗?
By taking away my only claim to fame?
如果你想让我开心
Well, if you wanted to make me happy,
可以给我讲个笑话啊
you could have told me a joke.
或者给我看个树袋熊和水獭
Or shown me a cute video of a koala and an otter
意外做朋友的可爱视频
becoming unlikely friends.
怎么对你都不算好啊
Oh, there is no winning with you.
再说树袋熊和水獭根本不生活在一个地方
And koalas and otters don't even live near each other!
所以才让他们的友谊变得意外啊!
That's what makes their friendship unlikely!
嘿
Hey!
你们在吵什么啊?
What's with all the yelling?
Leonard证明了我的元素并不存在
Leonard disproved my element.
现在所有的关注都随风而去了
Now all the attention is going to go away.
那不是很好  你一定很激动吧!
Oh, that's great. You must be thrilled!
到此为止! 我现在只有7位朋友了
That's it! I'm down to seven friends.
他是算上了霍比特人和超级英雄  是吧?
He's counting hobbits and superheroes, right?
当我以为元素是存在的时候  我并不想得到它
When I thought the element was real, I didn't want it.
但是现在Leonard证明了它不存在
But now that Leonard made it not exist,
我想要它胜过世界上的所有东西啊
I want it more than anything in the world.
那元素从来就没存在过啊
The... the element never existed.
又不是我抢走的  是科学抢走的啊
I didn't take it away, science took it away.
生科学的气去吧
Be mad at science.
你怎么敢拿科学来堵我
Don't you dare use science against me.
科学是我最好的朋友!
Science is my best friend!
太好了  我又有8位朋友了
Oh, good, I'm back up to eight.
你能不能告诉他  他已经疯了
Will you tell him he's out of his mind.
其实  我懂他说的话
Actually, I get what he's saying.
太好了! 9位!
Oh, yes! Nine!
欢迎回来  哥们儿
Welcome back, buddy.
就像你在和你不怎么喜欢的男生约会
It's like if you're dating someone you're not that into,
然后他们跟你分手了
and then they break up with you
然后你更想得到他们了
and then you want them more than ever.
我完全不知道她在说什么
I have no idea what she's talking about.
但是我们组团对抗你  所以我赞同
but we're ganged up on you so I agree.
算了  Sheldon  你到底想让我怎么样
Okay, Sheldon, what do you want me to do,
把实验结果藏起来吗?
hide the information?
就算我不发表
If I don't publish it,
迟早会有人发表的
it's just a matter of time before someone else does.
不不不  你当然得发表
No, no, of course you have to publish.
这是你作为科学家的责任
That's your responsibility as a scientist.
不然就违背职业道德了
Doing otherwise would be unethical.
你别无选择
You have no choice.
行  我会发表的
Fine, I'll publish.
这家伙简直让人难以置信啊
Can you believe this guy?
哇! Raj把碗给洗了
Aw! Raj did the dishes.
你怎么知道不是我洗的?
How do you know I didn't do them?
因为有一次  所有的刀都没洗
Because once, when all the knives were dirty,
你直接用钥匙切的面包
you cut a bagel with your keys.
早上好  各位
Good morning, everybody.
我出去买了咖啡
I picked up coffee while I was out.
Bernadette  这是你的薄荷摩卡加豆奶
Bernadette, here's your soy peppermint mocha.
哇  你不需要帮我买的
Aw, you didn't have to do that.
荣幸之至啊
Oh, my pleasure, and don't worry
还有  别担心你今天的演讲
about your presentation today.
你会表现很棒的
You're gonna be great.
没错  你一定会完美收工的
Yeah, you're gonna knock it out of the park.
我今天做的是什么演讲?
What presentation do I have today?
去吧
Just go.
他爱你哦
He loves you.
你在干吗?
What are you doing?
你想让我这么没面子么?
Are you trying to make me look bad?
我就想做个好客人啊
I'm just being a good house guest.
才不是  你是在扮演一个比我更好的丈夫角色
No, you're being a better husband than I am.
洗碗  买咖啡
Doing the dishes, getting coffee,
了解她的生活...
knowing about her life...
谁会这么做啊?
who does that?
拜托  我也给你买了一杯啊
Oh, come on, I brought you one, too.
我不想喝咖啡
I don't want coffee.
所以我买了热巧克力
That's why I got you hot chocolate.
快给我
Give me that.
别在让我出丑了行么
Just stop showing me up.
Howard  你听我说
Howard, listen to me.
你是个好丈夫
You're a great husband.
当然你的倾听技术还有待加强
Yes, your listening skills could use some work.
但是作为一个被母亲溺爱大的独生子
But it's amazing how far you've come given that you're
你已经做得很棒了
an only child raised by an over-protective mom.
这是不是变得有点诡异?
Um, is this getting weird?
等下
Hang on.
确实很诡异
So, yes.
嘿
Hey.
我就是想通知你我已经把实验结果发表了
I just wanted to let you know that I-I posted my findings.
我看见了
I saw.
我刚才
And I just
发出了收回我论文的声明
posted a retraction of my paper.
现在整个科学界都知道我犯错了
Now the whole scientific community knows I was wrong.
这是常有的事  Sheldon
These things happen all the time, Sheldon.
对我来说不是
Not to me.
我唯一收回的另一件事便是
The only other retraction I ever had to issue
在我七岁时承认我哥哥是
was when I was seven and I conceded that my brother
德克萨斯东部最好的忍者
was the greatest ninja in East Texas.
但那只是能让我的脑袋从他腋窝下解脱的策略而已
But that was just a ploy to get my face out of his armpit.
你在这呢!
There he is!
这不是我最爱的超级英雄:
It's my favorite superhero
回收侠吗!
the Retractor!
拜托了  别让他不好过
Come on, don't give him a hard time.
抱歉啦  Cooper
I'm sorry, Cooper.
我"收回"这句话
I retract it.
顺便说一句  Hofstader
By the way, Hofstadter,
驳回中国团队的发现这事干的太好了
nice job disproving the Chinese team.
这没什么大不了的
It's not a big deal.
这很重要好不好
It's a huge deal.
Cooper  也许干物理不是你的强项
Cooper, maybe physics just isn't your thing.
你有没有想过在零售业谋一份工作?
Have you ever considered a career in retail?
这样你就能靠回收东西养家糊口了
That way you could take things back for a living.
好了  Barry  到此为止
Okay, Barry, that's enough.
噢不  这没关系
Oh, no, that's okay.
我的仗我自己来打
I can fight my own battles.
你说对吧  "Bawwy"
Isn't that right, "Bawwy."
这是...?
Is...?
你这是戳我言语障碍的痛处吗?
Is that a reference to my speech impediment?
这太伤人了
That's pretty hurtful.
我...
I...
我没法控制它
I can't control it.
你说得对
You're right,
这太没必要了
That was uncalled for.
我收回这句话
I take it back.
当然你会啦
Of course you do.
因为你是回收侠啊!
Because you're the Retractor!
Raj  这顿饭太美味了
Raj, this dinner was amazing.
如果你再住久点
If you're here much longer,
我得去买大一号的衣服了
I'm gonna have to buy bigger clothes.
说什么呢
Nonsense.
你需要长点肉
You need a little fattening up.
你最近看起来太消瘦了
You've been looking too skinny lately.
真贴心
Aw.
Howie  为什么你从来不说像这么贴心的话呢?
Howie, how come you never say anything sweet like that?
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
还记得上周  我问你
Remember last week, when I asked you
是不是穿着塑身衣结果你没穿么?
if you were wearing Spanx and you weren't?
这有什么区别吗?
How's that different?
也许你能试着变得更体贴周到
Maybe you could try being more thoughtful,
像你的朋友Raj一样
like your friend Raj.
是吗  也许你也能试着变得更像他一样
Yeah, well, maybe you could try being more like Raj.
噢  真的吗?
Oh, really?
真的  那当然
Yeah, yeah.
他早上帮我准备了午餐
He packed me a lunch this morning.
里面还有张便条写着"去打败他们"
And there was a note inside that said, "Go get 'em""
好像我做的还不够一样
Like I don't do enough around here.
现在我还得帮你准备午餐?
Now I need to pack your lunch?
顺便说一句，  你为什么需要一张便条来告诉你
And by the way, why do you need a note telling you
"去打败他们"? 你是个成年人好吗!
to "go get 'em"? You're a grown man!
你应该知道"去打败他们"
You should know to "go get 'em"!
我确实知道"去打败他们"
I do know to "go get 'em""
但有时候当我"出去"并"打败他们"的时候
but sometimes it's nice to have emotional support
有这种精神支持感觉很好!
when I'm going and getting them!
嘿  你们能听见自己在说什么吗?
Hey, hey, do you hear yourselves?
让我们都冷静下退一步讲
Let's just, you know, all calm down and take a step back.
这太傻了
This is stupid.
我们为什么要吵架?
Why are we fighting?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我猜我就是感觉
I guess I was just feeling
自己像是个差劲的丈夫
like I'm a lousy husband.
你不是个差劲的丈夫
You're not a lousy husband.
你是个好丈夫
You're a great husband.
我才感觉我自己是个差劲的妻子呢
I was the one feeling like a lousy wife.
你说什么呢? 你是最好的妻子
Are you kidding? You're the best.
我知道问题所在了
I know what the problem is.
就是他!
It's him!
我招谁惹谁啦?
Oh, what did I do?
你让我们觉得我们不够努力
You made us feel like we're not trying hard enough.
就是  我们本来在婚姻的中途好好的
Yeah, we were totally fine half-assing our marriage
直到你出现
till you showed up.
听着  我很抱歉你们对我很生气
Look, I'm sorry you're upset with me,
但我就是想说很高兴看到
but I just have to say it's nice to see
你们站在同一阵线
the two of you on the same page.
是啊  感觉真的很好
Oh, it does feel good
你终于挺了我一次
to have you backing me up for once.
我一直挺你的好不好! 这也太...
I back you up all the time! That is not...
他又故技重施了! 你丫有病吗?!
He's doing it again! What is wrong with you?!
我真不敢相信他们赶你出来了
I can't believe they kicked you out.
我不敢相信他们竟然还没离婚
I can't believe they're still married.
噢糟了  我把肉桂儿的牙刷忘在Howard家了
Oh, no, I forgot Cinnamon's toothbrush at Howard's.
我想你又得和你爹地我合用啦
I guess you're sharing with Daddy again.
需要我打电话给善待动物组织请叫一声
Bark once if you need me to call PETA.
这只动物在我们公寓做什么呢?
What's that animal doing in our apartment?
别激动  她在箱子里出不来
Oh, relax, she's in her crate. She can't get out.
我给你五个字:
I have two words for you:
侏罗纪公园
Jurassic Park.
这些天真是每况愈下啊
This day just keeps getting worse and worse.
如果能让你好过点...
You know, if it makes you feel any better...
我估计不能
It probably won't.
估计你是对的
You're probably right.
Sheldon  多美的夜晚啊
Sheldon, it's a beautiful night.
要不你和我一起去散个步吧?
Why don't you and I go for a nice walk together?
是不是每件事都能让你性致盎然啊?
Oh, everything is just sex with you isn't it?
Sheldon  我想你可能找到了
Sheldon, I think you might find the support
你一直在寻找的支持  如果你能意识到
you're looking for, if you realize
感情有付出和回报
that relationships are a give and take.
只有你对她不离不弃
She can only be there for you
她才会一直在你身边
as much as you are for her.
谢谢你  Rajesh
Thank you, Rajesh.
还有  Amy  你得对Sheldon耐心点
And, Amy, you need to be patient with Sheldon,
别老给他施压让他接受你想要的那种亲密
instead of pressuring him to accept intimacy on your terms.
你还是走人吧
You should probably go.
我是Ira Flatow  这里是科学星期五
I'm Ira Flatow, and this is Science Friday.
让我们欢迎Sheldon Cooper博士回来
I'd like to welcome back Dr. Sheldon Cooper,
他认为自己发现了
who thought he had discovered
一种新型的超重元素却不料被
a new super-heavy element only to have it disproved
我的另一位嘉宾Leonard Hofstadter博士驳回
by my next guest, Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
欢迎来到科学星期五  先生们
Welcome to Science Friday, gentlemen.
-谢谢 -谢谢你
-Thanks. -Thank you.
Ira  请允许我
Ira, if I may, I'd like to apologize
为我上周的行为致歉
for my behavior last week.
这没关系
It's all right.
难道你没有什么对我想说的吗?
Now, isn't there something you'd like to say to me?
没有
No.
好的  Hofstadter博士
Now, Dr. Hofstadter.
能否给我们讲述一下你
Can you walk us through the process
驳回他理论所用的方法呢?
you used to disprove his theory?
-嗯... -我想我可以回答
-Well... -I believe I can answer that.
他问的是我
He asked me.
好吧
Fine.
就像我说的...
As I was saying...
你说的不对 Ira...
You're telling it wrong. Ira...
为了能真正了解事情的始末
to really understand the story here,
你得从头开始
you have to start at the very beginning:
在德克萨斯州东部的小镇里  有一个年轻的天才叫做...
A small town in East Texas, where a young genius named...
-Sheldon... -对的  叫Sheldon Cooper
-Sheldon... -That's right, Sheldon Cooper.
在他被邻居家的狗咬了之后
He was bitten by his neighbor's dog,
引导了他第一个科学发现
leading to his first scientific breakthrough--
狗狗死亡射线
the doggie death-ray.
可惜的是  他失败了
Which, sadly, he couldn't build
因为圣诞老人没得带给他所需的浓缩铀
because Santa wouldn't bring him enriched uranium.
我的意思是  我比较希望能听Hofstadter博士讲讲
I mean, I'd really like to hear it from Dr. Hofstadter,
如果你不介意
if it's okay with you.
真是奇了怪了
What a surprise.
你把我请回来就是为了无视我么?
Did-did you invite me back just so you could ignore me?
事实上  我根本没邀请你
Actually, I didn't invite you.
你进来  找了个座
You came in, you took a seat,
而且我对这种对峙感到很不舒服
and I'm not comfortable with confrontation.
Sheldon  这个采访应该是和我有关的
LEONARD: Sheldon, this interview is supposed to be about me.
好吧  这也太无趣了
Well, that seems like a snooze.
甚至对公共广播电台来说
Even for public radio.
你知道吗  如果他们每说一句丢人的话
You know, if we did a shot every time
我们都喝一杯
they said something embarrassing,
这绝对会是个翻天覆地的饮酒赛
this would be one hell of a drinking game.
现在喝酒早了点吧  是不是?
A little early for alcohol, isn't it?
你要知道  我不止能发表犀利的科学观点
SHELDON: You know, I don't just say smart things about science.
我还会约德尔唱法
I also yodel.
我去拿伏特加
I'll get the vodka.